# Shamayal Syed



647 - 544 - 0390



shamayal.syed@zurich.com



in www.linkedin.com/in/shamayal-syed

### Profile

Quick learning and detail-oriented individual who is currently an underwriting associate intern at Zurich Insurance Company. Enthusiastic about expanding on skills acquired from work experience in insurance, and healthcare research, and applying theoretical knowledge from the Zurich Insurance Pathways Program to seek out new opportunities as a market facing underwriting associate. Strongly driven to network and learn from experienced individuals in the insurance industry as I start my career.

#### Skills

## Computer Skills

- Proficient with MS Office (Excel, Word)
- DOS based policy production system
- **Underwriting Desktop**
- eFile
- iDocs

#### **Effective Communicator**

- Conducted interviews with study participants
- Prepared written research study protocols and grant proposals

#### **Data Analysis**

- Used R program for statistical analysis
- Recorded data through REDCap and Excel

#### Education

Underwriting Associate Program

**Zurich Insurance Pathways** Program (ZIPP)

Trained for technical and soft skills and learned about underwriting and the new business process

**Honours BSc** 

2017 - 2021

2022

University of Toronto (UofT)

Specialist in Health and Disease, Major in Cell and Systems Biology Courses: Statistics

## **Work Experience**

#### ZIPP Intern, Auto Team

Jun 2022 - present

#### **Zurich Insurance Company**

- Used Excel and BusinessObjects in the business renewal process to prepare essential documents such as loss runs, loss ratio, trade and economics sanctions manual screening tool, and sanctions checklist
- Completed account summary and fleet rater documents with information on claims history and vehicle/driver records from brokers and forwarded it to underwriters for review
- Collaborated with underwriters and underwriting associates to support them in going through the eFile application and uploading missing documents for renewed businesses
- Edited and updated policies with accurate information on premiums and endorsements, and completed issuances for business renewals using iDocs
- Reviewed and ensured policy wordings matched data from the binder such as policy term, liability coverage, and premiums
- Verified current and past values of premium and broker commission of various accounts using PMS, a DOS based policy production system

## **KITE Research Project Student**



Aug 2020 - Jan 2022

### Toronto Rehabilitation Institute, University Health Network

- Completed a thesis project with the Dementia Ageing Technology Engagement Lab on using remotely controlled technology to mitigate the impact of social isolation on people with dementia in LTCHs
- Designed a comprehensive study on how long-term care home (LTCH) workers can administer care to patients using remote technology, in collaboration with leading researchers and analyze its impacts using qualitative and quantitative data
- Interviewed seven LTCH staff during a five-week pilot study of an implementation project to gather feedback
- Secured a \$5000 grant from the Canadian Consortium of Neurodegeneration in Aging (CCNA) for a project which promoted communication for people with dementia